Guide to the Dept. of Human Development records,1937-2008.
Dept. of Human Development records, 1937-2008
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dept. of Human Development records, 1937-2008.
23-13-1868
New York State College of Human Ecology.Department of Human Development.
12.7 cubic ft.
Data sheets, survey forms, memos, interview material, articles, minutes, review files, memoranda, photographs, correspondence, videocassettes, and audiocassettes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Data sheets from a survey done in a course, "Orientation in Child Development 100"; sheets entitled "Child Preferences of Food," "Description of Early Home," "Important Factors in Early Childhood," "Community Provisions for Child Welfare," "Early Play Materials," "Garment Remembered Most Vividly," and "Books Read."
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
In 1925 the Dept. of Family Life was organized and in 1945 the name was changed to the Dept. of Child Development and Family Relationships. In 1969 the name changed to Human Development and Family Studies and during the 1998-99 year it was shortened to Human Development
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Data sheets from a survey done in a course, "Orientation in Child Development 100"; sheets entitled "Child Preferences of Food," "Description of Early Home," "Important Factors in Early Childhood," "Community Provisions for Child Welfare," "Early Play Materials," "Garment Remembered Most Vividly," and "Books Read."
Survey forms, memos, interview material and articles for a project conducted by Professor Harold Feldman, to study a first baby's effect on his parents' relationship with each other. The project was supported by a grant from the United States Public Health Service.
Includes videos of Steven Ceci on ABC's 20/20 and the McNeil-Lehrer News Hour in 1993 and one by Cynthia Hazen entitled "Relationships in the 90's" the other "Work and Family: Exploring the Issues" by Eileen Trzcinski and Elaine Wethington.
Includes faculty meeting minutes, external review files, department memoranda, colloquia information, photographs, and correspondence.
Includes preschool intelligence tests such as: Stanford-Binet, Rorschach, Illinois test of psycholinguistic abilities, Holtzman inkblot technique and Gesell.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Human Ecology.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Ceci, Steven.; Feldman, Harold, 1917-; Trzcinski, Eileen.; Wethington, Elaine.; New York State College of Home Economics.Dept. of Child Development and Family Relations.; New York State College of Home Economics.Dept. of Family Life.; New York State College of Human Ecology.Dept. of Human Development and Family Studies.
Subjects:
Child development--Research.; Home economics--Research.; Human ecology--Research.; Family--Study and teaching.; Parent and child--Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Surveys.; Videotapes.; Audiotapes.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
Additional material and digital versions can be found online here: http://ecommons.library.cornell.edu/handle/1813/531
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence and Chairman's Files
Box 11- Folders: 15-30, Box 4- Folder: 15, Box 20 - Folders: 19-22, Boxes 26-27
Series II. Faculty Meeting Minutes and Memos
Box 2, Box 4- Folders: 20-22, Box 9, Box 11- Folders: 1-14, Box 20 - Folders: 11-15
Series III. Projects and Reports; Faculty Annual Reports
Box 1, Box 2- Folders: 40-43, Box 7- Folders: 1-9, Box 19, Box 20- Folders: 16-18; Box 24- Folders: 1-50, Box 25- Folders: 1-12, Box 26- Folders: 1,2, Box 27- Folders: 6, 19-23
Series IV. Subject Files
Box 3- Folder: 5; Box 4, Folders: 2, 11-12, 14, 16-19, 23-25; Box 5- Folders: 1-6
Series V. Committees
Box 4- Folders: 3-10, 13; Box 5- Folders: 7-8; Box 11- Folders: 31-33, Box 26- Folders: 7-8, Box 27- Folders: 26-27
Series VI. Course Material
Box 3- Folders: 1-2; Box 6; Box 8; Box 14
Series VII. Dept. Reviews
Box 3- Folders: 3-4; Box 10; Box 13
Series VIII. Photographs, Slides
Box 4- Folder: 1; Box 12
Series IX. Intelligence Tests
Box 15-18
Series X. Colloquia and Symposiums
Box 20 - Folders: 1-10
Series XI. Videos, Cassette Tape Recordings, DVDs
Series XII. Extension Material
Box 21- Folders: 1-49; Box 22- Folders: 1-8
Series XIII. Programs
Box 29- Folders: 4-6
Series XIV. Publications
Box 22- Folders: 9-11
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence and Chairman's Files
  - Dean's Correspondence to the Dept/Chair, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Dean's Correspondence to the Dept/Chair, 1982-1988 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Dean's Correspondence to the Dept/Chair, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Dean's Correspondence to the Dept/Chair, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Dean's Correspondence to the Dept/Chair, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Dean's Correspondence to the Dept/Chair, 1993-1996 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Dean's Correspondence to the Dept/Chair, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 1998-01-1998-02 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 1998-06-1998-08 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 1998-09-1998-10 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 1998-11-1999-01 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 1999-02-1999-04 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 1999-03-1999-05 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 1999-05-1999-06 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 1999-07-1999-09 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 1999-10-1999-12 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 2000-01-2000-08 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 2000-09-2001-01 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 2001-02-2001-12 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence from the Chair to the HD Dept., 2002-01-2002-05 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Day Care Correspondence- Freezing of Day Care Research Program Director, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Curriculum Correspondence, 1993-2008 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Chairman - Steve Hamilton's Files
  - Correspondence, 1992-1996 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence concerning Extension, 1994-1999 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Chairman - Steve Robertson's Files
  - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 12-13)
  - Children, Youth, Families, and Communities - Faculty and Staff Expertise and Interests, 1997, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Early Childhood Program - transformation from the Nursery School, 1987-1993 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Early Childhood Position, 1991-1995 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Early Childhood Program, 1994-1996 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Early Childhood Program, 1997-1999 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Early Childhood Program, 2000s (Box 27, Folder 5A)
  - Department Report to the Dean, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - HDFS Proposal Processing Log, 1987-1992 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Extension Budget, 1992-1995 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Extension Budget, 1995-1997 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Extension Planning, 1992-1997 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Retention; Faculty Code of Conduct, 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Family Life Development Center, 1990-1991 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Graduate Teaching, 1993-1997 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Graduate Teaching, 1989-1992 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Instruction, 1990-1996 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Migrant Program, 1990-1995 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Space and Resource Allocation, 1990-1994 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Undergraduate Teaching, 1990-1996 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Undergraduate Teaching - Intro Course - HDFS 150 with a Gerontology Concentration, 1992-1997 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Chairman - John Eckenrode's Files
  - External Grants, Indirect Cost Agreements with FLDC/BLCC, 2000-2001 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Work Force Planning, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Work Force Planning, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence to/from the Dean, 2000-2002 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence to/from Associate Dean, 1999-2000 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Articles about Ranking Programs, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Minority Recruitment/Retention, 1998-2000 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Civil Rights Review, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Extension - Parenting Position, 2000-2001 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Funding Opportunities, 1999-2000 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Cooperative Extension, 2000-2001 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - Cooperative Extension, 2001-2002 (Box 27, Folder 36-37)
  - Cooperative Extension, 2002-2003 (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - Cooperative Extension Symposium, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - Psychopathology Program, 1997-2003 (Box 27, Folder 40)
  - Migrant Program, 2001-2003 (Box 27, Folder 41)
- Series II. Faculty Meeting Minutes and Memos
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1985-09-1985-12 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1988-09-1988-12 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1989-01-1989-04 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1989-05-1990-03 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1990-03-1990-06 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Department Memos, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Department Memos, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Department Memos, 1975-1976-05 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Department Memos, 1976-06-1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Department Memos, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Department Memos, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Department Memos, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Department Memos, 1982-10-1983-08 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Department Memos, 1983-09-1984-08 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Department Memos, 1984-09-1985-08 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Department Memos, 1987-03-1989-09 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Department Memos, 1989-10-1990-01 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Family Matters Project (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Marsicano Report- "At Risk" Pre-School Children, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Memos to HDFS Faculty, 1990-09-1990-12 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Memos to HDFS Faculty, 1990-04-1990-08 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Memos to HDFS Faculty, 1990-01-1990-03 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Memos to Faculty, 1991-01-1991-12 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Memos to Faculty, 1992-01-1992-02 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Memos to Faculty, 1992-03-1992-09 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Memos to Faculty, 1992-10-1993-02 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Memos to Faculty, 1993-03-1993-06 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Memos to Faculty, 1993-07-1993-12 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Memos to Faculty and Faculty Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1994-01-1994-04 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Memos to Faculty and Faculty Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1994-05-1994-10 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Memos to Faculty and Faculty Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1994-11-1995-01 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Memos to Faculty and Faculty Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1995-02-1995-12 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Memos to Faculty and Faculty Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1996-01-1996-08 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Memos to Faculty and Faculty Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1996-09-1997-01 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Memos to Faculty and Faculty Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1997-02-1997-07 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Memos to Faculty and Faculty Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1997-08-1997-12 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, Fall 1990-Spring 1991 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1991-09-1992-08 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, Fall 1992- Spring 1993 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, Fall 1993-Spring 1994 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, Fall 1994- Spring 1995 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1995-09-1997-08 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1996-09-1997-08 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1997-09-1998-08 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1998-09-1999-08 (Box 11, Folder 9,10)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1999-09-2000-08 (Box 11, Folder 11,12)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 2000-09-2001-08 (Box 11, Folder 13,14)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 2001-09-2002-08 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 2002-09-2003-04 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 2003-09-2004-07 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 2004-09-2004-12 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 2005-01-2005-05 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 2007-04-2008-06 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Series III. Projects and Reports
  - First Child Study- Information about the project done by Professor Feldman, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - First Child Study- Various forms and memos, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - First Child Study- Interview material, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - First Child Study- Articles related to the topic, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - First Child Study- papers from other institutions sent to Harold Feldman, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Family Matters Project (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Marsicano Report- "At Risk" Pre-School Children, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - "At Risk" Children's Program- goals, design, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Budget (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Parent Program (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Social Worker (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - First Year Report- "At Risk" Program, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Second Year Report- "At Risk" Program, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Third Year Report- "At Risk" Program, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Final Report- "At Risk" Program, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Careers After Cornell in Human Development, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 1995-1996 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 1997-1998 (Box 19, Folder 7A)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 1998-1999 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 2001-2002 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Academic Planning and Budgeting Conference Reports, 2002-2003 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Governance Structure in HDFS, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Annual Report Information, 1981-1982 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Department Annual Reports, 1991-1995 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Department Annual Reports, 1999-2000; 2000-2001; 2001-2002 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Department Annual Reports, 2002-2003; 2003-2004; 2004-2005 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Nursery School Annual Reports, 1977-1990 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Departmental Governance: Statement of Principles and Policies, 1998-10 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Dean's Ad Hoc Committee on Governance Report, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Strategic Plans and Summary for Strategic Planning Retreat in 1993, 1993, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Strategic Plan, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Faculty Annual Reports
    See additional faculty reports in electronic format in collection #23-2-2817
    - Anderson, Carol, 1980-1992 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, Carol, 1992-2002 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Beck, Sam, 1988-1991 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Birckmayer, Jennifer, 1975-1996 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Brumberg, Joan Jacobs, 1983-2003 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Casasola, Marianella, 2001-2003 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Castania, Kathleen, 1991-2002 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Ceci, Stephen, 1982-1992 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Ceci, Stephen, 1992-2003 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Cherry, Florence, 1978-1995 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Cochran, Moncrieff, 1981-2003 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Cornelius, Stephen, 1984-2003 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Crane, Betsy, 1995, 1992-1998, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Crosiar, Sally Jo, 2003 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Dean, Christiann, 1982-2003 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Dempster-McClain, Donna, 1989-2002 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Depue, Richard, 1992-2003 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Eckenrode, John, 1984-1991 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Eckenrode, John, 1991-2007 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Embrey, Kay, 1983-2002 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Engman, Herbert J., 1979-1981 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Engman, Herbert J., 1981-1988 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Engman, Herbert J., 1988-2003 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Garbarino, James, 1994-2002 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Goggin, Stephen, 1980-1990 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Goggin, Stephen, 1990-2003 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Gonzalez, Eduardo, 2002-2003 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Greene, Katrina, 1997-2000 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Hamilton, Mary Agnes, 1990-2002 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Hamilton, Stephen, 1975-1992 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Hamilton, Stephen, 1993-2004 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Haugaard, Jeffrey, 1990-2003 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Hazan, Cynthia, 1989-2003 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Henderson, Charles, 1984-2003 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Howe, Georgia, 2000-2003 (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Koslowski, Barbara, 1974-1993 (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Koslowski, Barbara, 1994-2003 (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Lee, Lee C., 1985-1999 (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Lekies, Kristi, 2002-2003 (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Lust, Barbara, 1977-1992 (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Lust, Barbara, 1992-2003 (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - McCabe, Lisa, 2002-2008 (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Mead, June, 2002-2003 (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - Meador, Rhoda, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - Moen, Phyllis, 1978-1994 (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - Moen, Phyllis, 1994-2002 (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Nye, Mary, 1980-1996 (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - Palmer-House, Kathryn, 2002-2003 (Box 24, Folder 46)
    - Pillemer, Karl, 1990-1996 (Box 24, Folder 47)
    - Pillemer, Karl, 1996-2004 (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - Ricciuti, Henry, 1958-1998 (Box 25)
    - Robertson, Steven, 1988-2003 (Box 24, Folder 49)
    - Ross-Bernstein, Judith, 1989-2003 (Box 24, Folder 50)
    - Savin-Williams, Richard, 1981-2007 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Schaff, Nancy, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Schelhas-Miller, Christine, 1999-2003 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Segal, Harry, 2002-2003 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Temple, Elise, 2002-2006 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Wang, Qi, 2001-2003 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Ward, Patricia, 1982-1996 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Wejnert, Barbara, 1998-1999, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Wethington, Elaine, 1987-1994 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Wethington, Elaine, 1994-2003 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Whittington-Couse, Maryellen, 2002-2003 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Williams, Wendy, 1997-2003 (Box 25, Folder 12)
- Series IV. Subject Files
  - HDFS Space Concerns, 1969-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Department Chairman Searches, 1976-1991, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Chancellor's Award for Excellence in Teaching, 1978-1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - A.D. White Professors at Large, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Nursery School Memos and Correspondence, 1979-1993 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Human Development and Family Studies (HDFS) Department Logo, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Consulting, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Confidentiality, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Day Care Position Advertisements, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - HDFS Faculty Rosters, 1971-1991 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Job Descriptions, 1978-1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - SRCD, Conference (#1), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - SRCD, Conference (#2), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Minority Issues, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Child-Family Psychopathology Training Program (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - SRCD Party, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Department Stationary (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - SRCD (Society for Research on Child Development) Biennial Meeting, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Child Development Review, 1987-10 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Smith Lever Funds, 1994-1998 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Department Name Change, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Series V. Committees
  - Graduate Field Committee Meeting Minutes, 1969-1977 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Field Committee Meeting Minutes, 1978-1998-10 (Box 29, Folder 7A)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, 1975-10-1976-08 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, 1976-09-1980-03 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Committee Lists, 1992-1996 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Extension Affairs Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Ad Hoc Space Committee, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Full Professors Promotion, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - HDFS Planning Committee, 1975, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - HDFS Committee on Criteria for Promotion and Tenure, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Business Affairs Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Advisory Committee, Spring 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - HDFS Advisory Committee, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Day Care Research Program Search Committee, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Dean's Search Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Committee on Review of Procedures for Tenure and Promotions, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Undergraduate Affairs Committee, 1974-1978 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Undergraduate Affairs Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Undergraduate Affairs Committee, 1981-1999-05 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1976-1981 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1982-1987 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1989-1999 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Undergraduate Education Committee, 1984-1989 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Undergraduate Education Committee, 1990-1993 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Undergraduate Education Committee, 1994-1999 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Early Childhood Advisory Committee, 2005-2007 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Executive Committee, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1999-2001 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 2001-2003 (Box 27, Folder 27)
- Series VI. Course Material
  - Nursery School, 1970's (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Nursery School, 1980's (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Early Childhood Planning Courses, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Early Childhood Planning Courses, 1974-1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Community Infant Care Center, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Nursery School, 1970-1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - HDFS-Data Book, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - HDFS-Data Book, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - HDFS-NIMH-Site Visit-general information, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 3)